Guide to the Maxine Kumin Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- March 1990 Acquisition, 1940-1987; 17.12; (20 boxes)
  - Friends--old; non-poets; friends of family, 1981-1983 (Box 16)
  - Requests for interviews, 1983 (Box 16)
  - Anne Carpenter, 1982, undated (Box 16)
  - Nemerov, Howard, 1972-1977 (Box 16)
  - Fans, casual friends, infrequent correspondence, 1980-1983; 2 (Box 17)
  - Writers, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Annette Jaffee, 1979-1982 (Box 17)
  - Nemerov, Howard, 1967-1972 (Box 17)
  - Meredith, William, 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Meredith, William, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Don Hall book ( To Make a Prairie ), 1977-1984 (Box 17)
  - Nemerov, 1978 (Box 17)
  - Williams, Miller, 1969-1973 (Box 17)
  - Booth, Philip, 1962-1970 (Box 17)
  - Starbuck, George, 1969-1971, undated (Box 17)
  - The New Yorker, 1971 (Box 17)
  - Clifton, Lucille, 1969-1971 (Box 17)
  - Cornish, Sam, 1970, undated (Box 17)
  - Fitts, Dudley, 1959-1961 (Box 17)
  - Rodman, Seldon, 1967-1968 (Box 17)
  - Pack, Robert, 1973-1975 (Box 17)
  - Halperin, Daniel, 1974-1976 (Box 17)
  - Smith, Alice L., 1972-1978, undated (Box 17)
  - A. Jaffee, 1983 (Box 17)
  - Friends who are primarily writers--frequent correspondence, 1983-1984; 2 (Box 17)
  - Tillie Olsen, 1964-1969, undated (Box 17)
  - Princeton, 1981-1983, undated (Box 18)
  - Students, would-be writers from speaking engagements, 1982-1983, undated (Box 18)
  - Viking--Amanda and Dana Vaill, 1980-1985, undated (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous magazines, 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - USIA article, 1983 (Box 18)
  - Requests--miscellaneous, 1983-1985 (Box 18)
  - Speaking--completed, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Permissions to reprint poems, etc., 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - Requests for interviews, 1984 (Box 19)
  - The Wizard's Tears, undated (Box 20)
- May 1995 Acquisition, 1973-1990; 5.21; (6 boxes)
  The May 1995 acquisition contains correspondence, writings, and personal papers by or relating to Maxine Kumin. Writings include drafts of the story "A Durable Solution" and other short and unsorted works. There is correspondence with writers and friends, Curtis Brown, Viking and North Point Press publishers, and others. Other materials include financial records, clippings, recommendations, and material relating to speaking engagements.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 436.
  Purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 1995.
  - Friends, primarily writers, frequent correspondence, 1988 (Box 21)
  - MIT, 1986-1987 (Box 21)
  - Ploughshares, 1987 (Box 21)
  - Income, 1985 (Box 21)
  - Curtis Brown, 1983-1985 (Box 21)
  - Speaking completed, 1985 (Box 21)
  - Speaking--NO (or doubtful), 1984-1985 (Box 21)
  - Country Journal Magazine --articles and correspondence, 1979-1983, undated (Box 21)
  - Fans, casual friends, 1986-1988 (Box 21)
  - Friends, old; non-poets; friends of family, 1986-1988 (Box 21)
  - Speaking completed, 1989 (Box 21)
  - Income and invoices for books, 1984 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous magazine and presses, 1974-1987 (Box 21)
  - Boston University, 1988-1989 (Box 21)
  - Students, would-be writers etc. from speaking engagements, 1985-1987; 2 (Box 21)
  - Alaska notes "Solstice", 1986 (Box 21)
  - "Durable Solution" --drafts, etc., undated (Box 21)
  - Manuscript-- The Long Approach, undated (Box 22)
  - Friends who are primarily writers--frequent correspondence, 1986-1987, undated; 2 (Box 22)
  - Speaking engagements completed, 1977 (Box 22)
  - Serving as judge, 1978-1981 (Box 22)
  - Writers--well known, 1977 (Box 22)
  - Serving as judge, 1978-1981 (Box 22)
  - Students, would-be writers from speaking engagements, 1980 (Box 22)
  - Russell & Volkening, 1978 (Box 22)
  - Students, would-be writers, Bread Loaf, 1978 (Box 22)
  - Requests--miscellaneous, 1978-1980 (Box 22)
  - Recommendations, 1978-1980 (Box 22)
  - Speaking completed, 1980 (Box 22)
  - Princeton, 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous magazines, 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, undated (Box 22)
  - Worksheets-- Nurture, 1985-1988 (Box 22)
  - Novel--clips, undated (Box 22)
  - Poetry workshops--MIT, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Some poems to teach by, undated (Box 22)
  - Excerpts from other writers--to use in teaching, undated (Box 22)
  - Children's book ("Equine Project"), 1977 (Box 23)
  - Bone pile--children's poems, undated (Box 23)
  - The Long Approach, 1986, undated (Box 23)
  - North Point Press, 1987 (Box 23)
  - Godine Press, 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Writers, established, infrequent correspondence, 1989-1990; 2 (Box 23)
  - Serving as judge, 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Income, also some travel vouchers, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous magazines and presses, 1988-1989 (Box 23)
  - Nevertheless (work in progress), undated (Box 23)
  - ABC, undated (Box 23)
  - Buckley-Little catalog, 1984-1985 (Box 23)
  - "Cassandra Effect" (short story to revise), undated (Box 23)
  - Nurture (working typescript), undated (Box 23)
  - Autobiography--contemporary authors, 1988 (Box 23)
  - "A Durable Solution" (story), 1987 (Box 23)
  - Writers, established, infrequent correspondence, 1987-1988; 2 (Box 23)
  - Speaking completed, 1986-1987; 2 (Box 23)
  - Income--permissions, licenses, coyrights, etc., 1987 (Box 23)
  - Radcliffe, 1978-1983 (Box 23)
  - PEN American Center, also Poets & Writers, 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Recommendations, blurbs, 1985 (Box 23)
  - Worksheets--"The Cassandra Effect", 1983 (Box 24)
  - Foaling article, 1984 (Box 24)
  - Thoreau--Maine Woods article, undated (Box 24)
  - Heron article, untitled (Box 24)
  - Poets & Place--draft and xerox--Massachusetts Council on the Humanities lecture, undated (Box 24)
  - Fan mail, 1977-1978 (Box 24)
  - Farm, 1979-1982; 3 (Box 24)
  - Regis College commencement address, 1979 (Box 24)
  - Recommendations and blurbs, etc., 1978 (Box 24)
  - Dartmouth, 1979, undated (Box 24)
  - Children's plays--"Duchess" and "Voyage", 1973-1979 (Box 24)
  - Articles and reviews (non-fiction stuff), 1976-1977 (Box 24)
  - Children's story--work in process--worksheets, kids' poems, 1977-1978 (Box 24)
  - Princeton, 1977-1978 (Box 24)
  - Recomendations and blurbs, also serving as judge, 1977 (Box 24)
  - Curtis Brown, 1978 (Box 24)
  - Speaking completed, 1978 (Box 24)
  - Permissions to reprint poems, anthologies, tapes, 1977-1978 (Box 24)
  - Speaking completed, 1979 (Box 24)
  - McGraw Hill, 1975-1978 (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous magazines, 1977-1978 (Box 24)
  - Requests for poems, articles, reprint rights, 1977-1978 (Box 24)
  - The Retrieval System (correspondence with Viking, etc.), 1977-1979 (Box 24)
  - Viking Press (old stuff), 1974-1979 (Box 24)
  - Writers, former students, Breadloafers, 1977 (Box 24)
  - Writers--would-be, 1976 (Box 25)
  - Friends, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Curtis Brown, 1985-1988 (Box 25)
  - Friends, writers, frequent correspondence, 1989 (Box 25)
  - Students, would-be writers from speaking engagements, 1988-1989 (Box 25)
  - Speaking--completed, 1988 (Box 25)
  - NY Times, Butternut essays, 1987, undated (Box 25)
  - "Harry the Horse", undated (Box 25)
  - "What Good Is Gus?" -- Children's story, undated (Box 25)
  - "The Cassandra Effect", undated (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous magazines and presses, 1987-1988 (Box 25)
  - Farm and personal (medical) etc. documents, 1986, undated (Box 25)
  - Recommendations, blurbs, tenures, etc., 1987-1989 (Box 25)
  - Recommendations, blurbs, tenure evaluations, etc., 1986 (Box 25)
  - New England Review, 1978, undated (Box 25)
  - Poems--currently submitted, undated (Box 25)
  - Unsorted writings, undated; 7 (Box 26)
- March 2001 Acquisition, 1946-1999; 9.08; (10 boxes)
  The March 2001 acquisition contains writings, correspondence, and professional and personal papers dating predominantly from the 1990s. In addition to large files for the poetry collection Looking For Luck (1992), and the collections Women, Animals, and Vegetables (1994) and Inside the Halo and Beyond the Journey (1999), the group includes shorter writings, financial and legal records relating to publications, such as contracts and permissions, and publicity and reviews.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 118.
  Purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 2001.
  - Russell-Vockening, 1987 (Box 27)
  - Recommends, blurbs, tenure, etc., 1991-1993 (Box 27)
  - Bummer story, 1991 (Box 27)
  - Recommendations, blurbs, tenure, etc., 1989-1990 (Box 27)
  - Friends, writers, frequent correspondence, 1990 (Box 27)
  - Viking-Amanda Vaill, 1986-1990 (Box 27)
  - Copyright reversions and registrations, 1981-1991 (Box 27)
  - Contract agreements, 1964-1983; 2 (Box 27)
  - Income, contracts, etc., 1991 (Box 27)
  - Fans, casual friends, 1989-1991 (Box 27)
  - Students, would-be writers, from speakers, engagements, etc., 1991 (Box 27)
  - Writers, established frequent correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 27)
  - Speaking--completed, 1990 (Box 27)
  - Worksheets, 1988-1989; 2 (Box 27)
  - Income, contracts, etc., 1989-1990 (Box 28)
  - Farm., personal, medical, 1990; 2 (Box 28)
  - JEC Ballou, 1994 (Box 28)
  - Farm, personal, medical, 1993-1994 (Box 28)
  - Writers, established /infrequent correspondence, 1993-1994; 2 (Box 28)
  - Income contracts, 1993 (Box 28)
  - Students, would-be writers, 1992 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous magazines, 1991-1993 (Box 28)
  - Speaking completed, 1992-1994; 2 (Box 28)
  - Speaking -- no or doubtful, 1989-1994 (Box 28)
  - Speaking completed, 1992-1993; 2 (Box 29)
  - Academy of American Poets, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Curtis Brown, 1989-1990 (Box 29)
  - Speaking -- no or doubtful, 1986-1990 (Box 29)
  - Students, would-be writers from speaking engagements, 1990 (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous magazines, 1990 (Box 29)
  - Students, would-be writers from speaking engagements, 1994-1995; 2 (Box 29)
  - Deductibles, non-reimbursements, expenses, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Curtis Brown, 1991-1992 (Box 29)
  - Income, contracts, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Worksheets, 1993 (Box 29)
  - Requests for interviews, 1993-1995 (Box 29)
  - Gotlieb re: Kumin papers, 1967-1987 (Box 29)
  - University of Miami, 1994, undated (Box 29)
  - Reprint permissions, anthologies, etc., 1992-1993 (Box 29)
  - Mary Oliver review, 1993 (Box 30)
  - Friends, writers, frequent correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 30)
  - Friends, old non-poets, friends of family, 1989-1994; 2 (Box 30)
  - Sexton symposium (APA), 1992 (Box 30)
  - Serving as judge, 1989-1994 (Box 30)
  - NY Times -- Shakespeare & farm, 1995 (Box 30)
  - New York Times Book Review, 1992-1993, undated (Box 30)
  - Boston Globe, 1992 (Box 30)
  - Transactions -- Dori Katz, N. Kogon, 1990-1992 (Box 30)
  - Nurture reviews, etc., 1989-1990, undated (Box 30)
  - Requests, miscellaneous, 1986-1990 (Box 30)
  - Academy of American Poets, 1985-1987 (Box 30)
  - Fans, casual friend, 1992-1994 (Box 30)
  - Requests for interview, 1986-1992 (Box 30)
  - CV, publicity, articles, 1980-1993, undated (Box 30)
  - Friends, writers, frequent corresp[ondence], 1991-1992 (Box 30)
  - Speaking completed, 1991 (Box 30)
  - Permissions to reprint, anthols, Festschriften, etc., 1991 (Box 31)
  - Farm, personal, medical, 1991-1992 (Box 31)
  - NY Times, review of Second Nature, 1991 (Box 31)
  - Recommendations, blurbs, tenure revs., etc., 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - Norton luck, 1991-1993 (Box 31)
  - Photos, publicity clips, etc., 1976-1995 (Box 31)
  - Pitzer college, 1995-1997, undated (Box 31)
  - Academy of American Poets, 1995 (Box 31)
  - Kumin reviews, dissertation, 1991-1994 (Box 31)
  - Income contracts, 1996 (Box 31)
  - Deductible expenses: postage, donations books, etc., 1996 (Box 31)
  - Speaking -- completed, 1995 (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous magazines, etc., 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - Reprint permisions, anthologies, etc., 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - Income, contracts, 1995 (Box 31)
  - Pack anthology of favorite old poets, 1994, undated (Box 31)
  - Deductible, non-reimbursements, expenses, donated books, etc., 1995 (Box 31)
  - Requests, miscellaneous, 1991-1995 (Box 31)
  - New York Times Book Review, 1989-1990 (Box 31)
  - Writers, infrequent correspondence, 1997-1998; 2 (Box 31)
  - Empty envelope and printed material, undated (Box 31)
  - Norton, 1995-1997 (Box 31)
  - Farm, personal, medical, 1995-1997; 2 (Box 32)
  - Requests, miscellaneous, 1995-1998, undated (Box 32)
  - Reprint permissions, anthologies, 1996 (Box 32)
  - Students, would-be writers from speaking engagements, 1997 (Box 32)
  - Reprint permissions, anthologies, 1997 (Box 32)
  - Speaking, no or doubtful, 1994-1997 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous magazines, 1996-1997 (Box 32)
  - Friends, old, non-poets, friends of family, 1995-1996 (Box 32)
  - Serving as judge, 1995-1996 (Box 32)
  - Novel notes, 1994-1997 (Box 32)
  - New York Times Book Review, Gardens, 1997, undated (Box 32)
  - New York Times Book Review, Horse, 1997 (Box 32)
  - Tear sheets, articles, poems, 1988-1997 (Box 32)
  - Speaking completed, 1997; 2 (Box 32)
  - Library of Congress, 1989-1993 (Box 32)
  - Fans, casual friends, 1995; 2 (Box 32)
  - Recommendations, blurbs, tenure reviews, etc., 1996-1997 (Box 32)
  - Davidson College, 1996-1997 (Box 32)
  - Students, would-be writers from speaking engagements, 1996 (Box 33)
  - Speaking completed, 1996 (Box 33)
  - Writers established, frequent correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 33)
  - Inside the Halo and Beyond the Journey, 1999, undated; 5 (Box 33)
  - Looking for Luck, 1991-1993; 5 (Box 33)
  - Our Ground Time Here Will Be Brief, 1979 (Box 33)
  - Quit Monks, 1996, undated; 2 (Box 33)
  - "Stendhal and Dostoievski: Amorality and the Protagonist", 1946 February (Box 34)
  - Women, Animals, and Vegetables, 1993-1994, undated; 9 (Box 34)
  - "Beginning with Gussie", 1990 (Box 34)
  - "Breed", 1991 (Box 34)
  - "The Care Givers", 1990 (Box 34)
  - "The Cassandra Effect", 1993-1994, undated; 2 (Box 34)
  - "Children of Darkness", 1992-1993 (Box 34)
  - Connecting the Dots, 1996, undated; 2 (Box 34)
  - "Floatation Devices", 1991, undated (Box 34)
  - "Have Saddle, Will Travel", undated (Box 34)
  - "Hey Dude", 1993 (Box 34)
  - "A Horse for Fun", 1991 (Box 34)
  - "Jack: A Memoir", 1991, undated (Box 34)
  - "Jicama, Without Expectations", undated (Box 34)
  - Journal entries, undated (Box 34)
  - In Deep, 1986-1988 (Box 35)
  - Inside the Halo and Beyond the Journey, undated (Box 35)
  - Excerpts from a June Journal, 1991 (Box 35)
  - "The Match", 1993-1995; 2 (Box 35)
  - "Mutts", 1993 (Box 35)
  - "Off", 1996 (Box 35)
  - "Praise Be", undated (Box 35)
  - "Two Junes", 1996 (Box 35)
  - "The Volunteer", undated (Box 35)
  - Beacon Press, 1988-1990 (Box 35)
  - Children's books, 1988-1998, undated (Box 35)
  - Country Journal, 1988-1992 (Box 35)
  - Norton -- Women, Animals & Vegetables, 1992-1993 (Box 35)
  - Publicity and reviews, 1997-1998, undated (Box 35)
  - Poetry, 1994-1995, undated; 3 (Box 35)
  - Posters, 1992-1994, undated; 3 (Box 36)
- January 2005 Acquisition, 1969-2004; 5.63; (11 boxes)
  Organized into four subseries: Correspondence, Writings, Miscellaneous, and Audiovisual Material.
  The January 2005 Acquisition contains additional correspondence, writings, personal papers, and audiovisual material. In addition to large files of family correspondence, material relating to the poetry collection The Long Marriage (2001), and calendars, the group features sound recordings of poetry readings by Kumin and interviews.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 43-46 (sound and video recordings): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 47 (computer disk): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 739.
  Purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2005.
  - Correspondence
    - Joan Wang, 1977-2000; 2 (Box 37)
    - Family, 1972-1998; 10 (Box 37)
    - Curtis Brown, 1993 (Box 37)
    - Ontario Review Press, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Writers, established, infrequent, correspondents, 1995-1996; 2 (Box 37)
      Includes correspondence with Donald Hall, Josephine Jacobsen, Daniel Hoffman, and William Jay Smith.
    - Requests for interviews, 1996-1998 (Box 37)
    - Used books, etc., 1997 (Box 37)
    - Fans, casual friends, 1998 (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous magazines, 1998 (Box 37)
    - Anthologies, reprints, 1998 (Box 37)
    - Reprints, permissions, anthologies, 1998 (Box 38)
    - Serving as judge, 1998 (Box 38)
    - Speaking -- No or Doubtful, 1998-1999 (Box 38)
    - Writers A-N, 1998; 2 (Box 38)
      Includes correspondence with Carolyn Kizer, Daniel Hoffman, Josephine Jacobsen, Donald Hall, and Robert Pinsky
    - Friends, old, non-poets, circa 1998-2001; 2 (Box 38)
    - Records, blurbs, tenure reviews, 1998-2001 (Box 38)
    - Scott Waxman, 1998-2002 (Box 38)
    - Speaking completed, 1999; 2 (Box 38)
    - Fans, casual friends, 2000-2001 (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous magazines, 2000-2001 (Box 38)
  - Writings
    - Excerpts From a June Journal, undated (Box 38)
    - Unidentified autograph manuscript notes, typescripts, etc., undated; 2 (Box 38)
    - "The Quill-Lion and the Unicorn," drafts, typescript, with notes, undated (Box 38)
    - Set of loose corrected typescripts and photocopied pages, undated (Box 38)
    - "Subduing the Dream in Alaska", undated (Box 38)
    - Drafts of poems, mostly carbon copies of typescripts with some holograph corrections, circa 1969 (Box 38)
    - Worksheets, autograph manuscript notes, corrected typescripts, 1997-1998 (Box 38)
    - The Long Marriage, 1991; 7 (Box 39)
      Includes corrected typescripts; corrected printer's proof, first pass; corrected printer's proof, second pass; original black and white photograph (used as frontispiece); original mock-up for book, with corrections; corrected printer's proof, third pass
    - Women poets article for Sharon Bryan, 1991-1992 (Box 39)
    - Bringing Together, worksheets; corrected printer's proof, second pass; corrected printer's proof, first pass; original typescript, circa 2002; 4 (Box 39)
    - Worksheets, Jack and Other New Poems, typescripts, corrected, 2004 January 15; 2 (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Judy Kumin, typescript poems, undated (Box 39)
    - Newspaper clippings, photocopied articles, etc. for research or book reviews, undated; 4 (Box 39)
    - Mina, Maxine, Marianne...and More. Program for performance at Yale University, 2003 (Box 39)
    - Program for the 196th commencement at Bowdoin College, 2001 May 26 (Box 39)
    - Program books from events, etc., undated (Box 39)
    - Diary, 1975 (Box 39)
    - Calendars, 1978-1979 (Box 39)
    - Calendars, 1980-2002; 23 (Box 40)
    - Looking for Luck, 1991 (Box 40)
    - Deductibles, 2002 (Box 40)
    - Speaking completed, 2001 (Box 40)
    - Honorary degrees from various institutions, undated; 5 (Box 40)
    - Income, contracts: financial-related materials, 1997-2002; 4 (Box 40)
    - Florida International University, 1997-2000 (Box 41)
    - Norton, 1998 (Box 41)
    - "Four Poems," The American Poetry Review, Vol. 5/No. 5, 1976 (Box 41)
    - Articles for audience chapter, undated (Box 41)
    - Clippings, etc. related to Saul Simon, undated (Box 41)
    - Scrapbook containing clippings and photographs, 2004 January 24 (Box 42)
    - "Maxine Kumin Backup", 2004 January 24; (1 computer disk)
      Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services.
      2005-ycal-0105-a-0001
  - Audiovisual Material
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Audiocassettes
      - Maxine Kumin reading, Great Tapes, undated; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248311)
      - Interview with Maxine Kumin, WEVO, Concord, NH, undated; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248329)
      - Maxine Kumin, "Poems to a Listener with Henry Lyman", UMass, undated; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248337)
      - "Folger Poetry Cassette Series: Maxine Kumin", 1987 December; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248345)
      - "Maxine Kumin Compass", Great Tapes (1 of 3 audiocassettes), 1976 Spring; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248352)
      - "Maxine Kumin Compass", Great Tapes, Univ. of [Minnesota] (2 of 3 audiocassettes), 1976 Spring; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248360)
      - "Maxine Kumin Compass", Great Tapes (3 of 3 audiocassettes), 1976 Spring; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248378)
      - Maxine Kumin, Progress Report, "Selected Poems", 1977; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248386)
      - "Poetry Reading", Maxine Kumin, University of Arizona, 1981 February; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248394)
      - "Poets and Builders: Maxine Kumin", 1986; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248402)
      - Fresh Air, Maxine Kumin, 1987 May 29; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248410)
      - New Letters on the Air, Maxine Kumin, University of Missouri, K.C. (1 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248436)
      - New Letters on the Air, Maxine Kumin, University of Missouri, K.C. (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1987 December; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248428)
      - Poets in Person, Karl Shapiro, Maxine Kumin, 1991; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248444)
      - "Tribute to William Meredith", NY Historical Society, 1991 May 16; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248451)
      - "Maxine Kumin/Reed Wittemore, French Institute", The Academy of American Poets, 1992 February 18; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248469)
      - "Poetry Reading", Maxine Kumin/Nancy Willard, Brandeis University, 1992 March; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002091248477)
      - Howard County Poetry & Literature Society Presents "Maxine Kumin: Reading her Poetry", 1997 September 27; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248584)
      - The Writer's Almanac, Minnesota Public Radio (1 of 10 audiocassettes), 1997 June 2-8; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248501)
      - The Writer's Almanac, Minnesota Public Radio (2 of 10 audiocassettes), 1997 June 16; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248519)
      - The Writer's Almanac, Minnesota Public Radio (3 of 10 audiocassettes), 2000 June 5-11; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248485)
      - The Writer's Almanac, Minnesota Public Radio (4 of 10 audiocassettes), 2001 June 4-10; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248493)
      - The Writer's Almanac, Minnesota Public Radio (5 of 10 audiocassettes), 2001 April 30 - May 6; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248527)
      - The Writer's Almanac, Minnesota Public Radio (6 of 10 audiocassettes), 2002 May 6-12; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248535)
      - The Writer's Almanac, Minnesota Public Radio (7 of 10 audiocassettes), 2002 June 3-9; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248543)
      - The Writer's Almanac, Minnesota Public Radio (8 of 10 audiocassettes), 2002 June 3-9; 1; This appears to be a copy. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248550)
      - The Writer's Almanac with Garrison Keillor, Minnesota Public Radio (9 of 10 audiocassettes), 2002 June 17-23; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248568)
      - The Writer's Almanac, Minnesota Public Radio (10 of 10 audiocassettes), 2002 July 1-7; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002091248576)
    - Compact Discs
      - "The Hudson Review: Along These Lines", 2003 (Box 45)
      - "The Writer's Almanac", 2003-2004; (4 compact discs) (Box 45)
    - Video Recordings
      All video recordings are VHS format
      - "Carolyn Kizer Reading (Introduced by MK)", 1986 October 2; YCALMSS734_0001; 1; 00:48:31 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102338952)
      - "Bookmark (CSPAN), Donald Hall with Edward Hirsch and Maxine Kumin", 1990 May 24; YCALMSS734_0002; 1; 00:28:44 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102338960)
      - Four interviews with Maxine Kumin, 1986-1994; YCALMSS734_0003; 1; 01:48:35 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102338978)